<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>John Heaven</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on John Heaven</description>
    <image>
      <url>%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 11:39:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Ambient Data Logger for Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>/post/ambient-data-logger-for-rpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 11:39:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ambient-data-logger-for-rpi/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series on my ambient data logging and visualisation setup.
I&amp;rsquo;ve already given an overview of the entire architecture, and written about setting up the Raspberry Pico(s) as sensor devices. Now I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain how I collect that data in a CSV and Postgres database.
Dumb sensors The sensors themselves are designed to be quite dumb. They don&amp;rsquo;t log data locally because it&amp;rsquo;s easier to access it if it&amp;rsquo;s stored centrally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Building an Ambient Data API With the Raspberry Pico W</title>
      <link>/post/ambient-data-api-with-raspberry-pico/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 15:02:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ambient-data-api-with-raspberry-pico/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I gave an overview of how I collect ambient data using a Raspberry Pi and a couple of Raspberry Pico Ws. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give more detail on how to set up the Pico to take readings on demand via the network.
Equipment If you want to try this at home, you&amp;rsquo;ll need:
A Raspberry Pico W with MicroPython installed A soldering iron and paraphernalia (or another way of connecting the sensor to the Pico W such as breadboard and jumpers) A DHT-22 or BME280 sensor A wifi network Attaching a sensor to your Pico W The MicroPython code I wrote has support for two sensors: the DHT-22 and the BME280.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 0: Logging and visualising ambient data with a Raspberry Pico W</title>
      <link>/post/logging-ambient-data-raspberry-pico-grafana-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 12:49:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/logging-ambient-data-raspberry-pico-grafana-pi/</guid>
      <description>The Raspberry Pico W is a cheap microcontroller (around €8) that can control sensors and access a WIFI network. With a bit of soldering and MicroPython, you can have it serving JSON data over your local network, then log it with a database and visualise it in a dashboard. Here I&amp;rsquo;m just going to briefly describe my setup as the basis for later blog articles.
Overall setup Architecture diagram
Full-size image</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! I&amp;rsquo;m John Heaven.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been freelance for the past few years, working mainly in the areas of web development and technical communication. Now I&amp;rsquo;m looking for employment as a Data Engineer or Data Scientist.
Data Science Bootcamp and Hands-On Capstone Project In November 2022, I completed the Data Science Bootcamp at neuefische. I really enjoyed spending all day coding in Python for 12 weeks, working with scientists and people from other professional backgrounds, pair programming and problem solving in groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Hugo, the world&amp;#39;s fastest framework for building websites</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
